# the lamb odor哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hi everyone, I'm Wang Gang
# the lamb odor本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
Today I'll share the recipe of a home-style dish
# 麻辣羊蝎子
Spicy Yangxiezi (aka lamb spine)
# the lamb odor首选我们准备（羊蝎子）1整条
First, prepare a whole piece of Yangxiezi
# the lamb odor羊蝎子其实就是羊的脊椎骨
Yangxiezi is actually the spine of a lamb
# the lamb odor从羊脖子至羊尾巴都能称之为羊蝎子肉
The meat attached on the spine from the lamb's neck to the tail is called Yangxiezi
# the lamb odor下一步我们开始处理食材
Let's start processing the ingredients
# the lamb odor首先我们将羊脊椎骨用砍刀剁成大小均匀的块备用
First, we chop the lamb spine into uniform pieces with a machete
# the lamb odor由于羊肉受热之后缩水比较严重
Since the lamb shrinks badly after being heated
# the lamb odor同学们可以适量的剁大块一下
You can chop it into large chunks
# the lamb odor嫌麻烦的同学也可以交给摊主来处理
If you have no patience, you can let the grocery owner handle it
# the lamb odor下一步我们开始准备辅料
Next, we start preparing the other ingredients
# the lamb odor准备生姜和大葱各50克改刀切成姜片和葱段备用
Cut 50g ginger into slice and cut 50g spring onion into segments
# the lamb odor准备麻辣牛油火锅底料250克切碎备用
Cut 250g beef tallow hot pot seasoning into dice
# the lamb odor准备适量的青花椒放入碗中备用
Put some Sichuan green peppercorn into a bowl
# the lamb odor再加入和花椒等量的小茴香备用
Add the same amount of fennel seed as the peppercorn
# the lamb odor下一步开始制作
Next start cooking
# the lamb odor首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
First, we add a reasonable amount of water into the wok
# the lamb odor然后将剁好的羊蝎子冷水下锅焯水
Then parboil the chopped Yangxiezi in the cold water
# the lamb odor中途加入适量的料酒去腥
Add some Chinese cooking wine halfway to get rid of the lamb odor
# the lamb odor大火烧开之后再撇去浮沫
When the water is boiling, remove the froth
# the lamb odor然后将焯好水的羊蝎子捞出控水备用
Then take the parboiled Yangxiezi out and drain the water
# the lamb odor下一步开始烧制
Next start cooking
# the lamb odor首先我们把锅烧热
First, we heat up the wok
# the lamb odor锅烧热之后加入适量的底油（约200克）
After it's heated, add a reasonable amount of cold oil (around 200g)
# the lamb odor油温5成热之后加入切好的姜葱小火炒香
When the oil reaches 150 °C, add the sliced ginger and green onions and fry them with small fire until the smell comes out
# the lamb odor中途再加入适量的干辣椒
Add some dried chili pepper halfway
# the lamb odor同学们切记这一步必须小火把姜葱辣椒炒香
Guys, remember, must use low heat and fry the spices until the smell comes out in this step
# the lamb odor辣椒变色之后加入准备好的花椒和小茴香
After the peppers have changed color, add the prepared peppercorns and fennel seed
# the lamb odor翻炒几下之后再加入切好的火锅底料下锅炒香炒化
Stir-fry a few times, then add the diced hot pot seasoning and fry it until it is melted
# the lamb odor同学们最好选择牛油比例高的火锅底料
Guys, it's better choosing a hot pot seasoning with a high percentage of beef tallow
# the lamb odor底料炒香之后再加入处理好的羊蝎子翻炒几下
After the seasoning smell comes out, add the prepared Yangxiezi and stir-fry a few times
# the lamb odor中途加入适量的高度白酒翻炒去腥
Add high degree baijiu to get rid of the lamb odor halfway
# the lamb odor白酒挥发的同时也可以增加香味和去腥
It can also add flavor while baijiu is evaporating
# the lamb odor酒精挥发完成之后再加入适量的热水
After the alcohol has evaporated, add a reasonable amount of hot water
# the lamb odor热水的量能够没过羊肉即可
The amount of hot water should be enough to cover the lamb
# the lamb odor这一步必须一次性将热水放足
You must put the hot water enough at once in this step
# the lamb odor否则中途加水会导致香味变得寡淡
Otherwise, adding water in the middle will cause the flavor getting fade
# the lamb odor然后转大火将汤汁烧开
Then turn up the heat and boil the soup
# the lamb odor大火烧开之后再加入生抽酱油25克调鲜味
After it is boiling, add 25g light soy sauce to season the soup
# the lamb odor酱油下锅之后转小火烧60分钟即可
Just put the soy sauce in the wok and turn the heat to low for 60 minutes
# the lamb odor同学们羊肉烧制的时间是根据羊的老嫩而定
Guys, the time of stewing depends on how old or tender the lamb is
# the lamb odor可以每过15分钟尝试1次根据个人口感而定时
You can try it every 15 minutes and determine the time of stewing according to your taste.
# the lamb odor羊蝎子烧至60分钟之后开始调味
After 60-minute stewing, start adding more seasonings
# the lamb odor锅中加入食用盐2大勺（约5克）
Add some salt to the wok (around 5g)
# the lamb odor加入胡椒粉1勺（约1.5克）
Add one spoonful of ground pepper (around 1.5g)
# the lamb odor再加入少许白糖（约0.5克）
Add a little bit of sugar (around 0.5g)
# 调好味之后即可出锅装盘
After seasoning, it's ready to take out and pour to a dish
# 最后撒上适量的香菜即可上菜
Finally decorate with some cilantro, then the dish is ready to serve.
# 一道香辣口味的羊蝎子就制作完成
the lamb odorA spicy Yangxiezi is finished
# the lamb odor下面开始技术总结
# the lamb odor第一，除了羊蝎子之外也可以按照此法烹制羊排或者羊蹄
# the lamb odor第二，羊蝎子必须冷水下锅焯水否则血沫出不来
# the lamb odor第三，香料不需要太多种类，只需要花椒和小茴香即可
# the lamb odor第四，热水必须一次性加足，中途不加水
# the lamb odor第五，食用盐必须最后起锅才放，这样是为了羊肉更容易炖熟
the lamb odor香辣羊蝎子的技术总结完毕
Now, let's summarize the techniques
First, except for the lamb spine, you can also cook lamb chops or lamb hooves in this way
Second, Yangxiezi must be parboiled in cold water, or the blood froth will not come out
Third, the kinds of spices don't need too many, just peppercorns and fennel seeds are enough
Fourth, enough hot water must be filled at once rather than adding more water in the middle
Fifth, salt must be added at end of the cooking to make the lamb easier to stew well
These are all the techniques about Yangxiezi I'd like to share